# **Justin Dickinson**



Cell: (917) 226-8030

Email: jmdickinson@gmail.com

Twitter: @jmdickinson

I have spent my career as a jack of all trades for design and development. Beginning with my role as technical developer for a large agency and continuing with my experience as a Senior UX Designer at an NYC startup my jobs have always required multidisciplinary proficiency in interaction and user experience design as well as proficiency in project management, product development, and marketing/social media initiatives. I've spent my time on agile, small teams that share responsibilities for quick turn around and can iterate until perfect.



# Professional Experience

## **Senior UX Designer**

FiLife, New York, NY (2008 - Present)

- Began as one of two front-end developers shortly after site was founded
- Took over IA, design, and branding, eliminating need for third party agency
- Optimized site using CSS frameworks and modern best practices to make front-end more lightweight
- Created custom frameworks for rapid prototyping
- Overhauled entire site design and architecture multiple times as business developed and changed
- Worked closely with product, marketing, and sales teams to build projects and reach business goals through design and UX

#### **Interactive Developer**

*Martino Flynn, Rochester, NY (2006 – 2008)* 

- Joined a small team of designers to oversee engineering when they brought their web development in-house
- Collaborated to create site architectures and taxonomies for companies who previously had little or no web presence
- · Built and implemented web apps, Flash elements, and CMS solutions
- Oversaw front-end development and implemented AJAX/DHTML/PHP to bring client sites and applications up to date

# Interactive Developer, Project Manager Blend Studios, Rochester, NY (2004 – 2006)

- Co-founded startup in 2004
- Sought-out new clients through outreach, proposal writing, and case studies for local business landscape and competition
- Managed accounts ranging from local business branding to university application development
- Oversaw backend engineering of custom CMS solutions and front-end development of AJAX/DHTML sites and applications
- Copywriter for majority of web projects
- Print collateral design in tandem with web branding

#### **Proficiencies**

#### Design

A combination of Illustrator, Photoshop, and in-browser design using CSS frameworks and Firebug.

# **Front-end Development**

CSS, HTML, DHTML, Javascript, jQuery, 960 CSS grid framework, custom designed CSS frameworks. Wordpress and other CMS systems. Amazon Simple Pay, Paypal, Volusion, and Magneto for e-commerce solutions.

### **Backend Development**

PHP, symfony, and mysql

### **Testing and Optimization**

Silverback usability testing, Google optimizer, AB and multi-variant testing.

#### **Education**

# B.Sc. New Media Information Technology, Rochester Institute of Technology, 2005

- Concentration in Front-End Development and Multimedia design
- Course work in project management; group management; UX design, Information Architecture, GUI design and testing; usability and human factors studies
- Programming in HTML, DHTML, Javascript, CSS, PHP, MySQL etc.; CMS development; animation; video editing and typography

#### **Interests**

UX Design as solution. Information Architecture. Creating beautifully usable applications and web sites. Rapid prototyping. New solutions for front-end development. Social media, social gaming, social applications. Mobile development. Writing, cooking, NYC, and food.

#### Portfolio

View annotated work samples

#### References

Available on request